<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Polygon &#8211; SingleClickBlog</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/polygon/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:56:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Spectacular designs of animals in polygonal style</title>
		<link>/2018/10/06/spectacular-and-colorful-designs-of-animals-in-polygonal-style/</link>
					<comments>/2018/10/06/spectacular-and-colorful-designs-of-animals-in-polygonal-style/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xczer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Polygon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/?p=343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Digital art is an artistic work or practice that uses digital technology as an essential part of the creative or presentation process. Since the 1970s,...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Digital art is an artistic work or practice that uses digital technology as an essential part of the creative or presentation process.</p>
<blockquote><p>Since the 1970s, various names have been used to describe the process, including computer art and multimedia art. Digital art is itself placed under the larger umbrella term new media art.</p></blockquote>
<p>The techniques of digital art are used extensively by the mainstream media in advertisements, and by film-makers to produce visual effects. Desktop publishing has had a huge impact on the publishing world, although that is more related to graphic design.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-346" src="http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/small-poly-3332793_1280-1024x682.jpg" alt="" width="718" height="478" /></p>
<p>Both digital and traditional artists use many sources of electronic information and programs to create their work.</p>
<p>Given the parallels between visual and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_art" target="_blank" rel="noopener">musical arts</a>, it is possible that general acceptance of the value of digital visual art will progress in much the same way as the increased acceptance of electronically produced music over the last three decades.</p>
<h3>Contents</h3>
<ul>
<li>Computer-generated <strong>visual media</strong></li>
<li>Computer generated 3D still imagery</li>
<li>Computer generated animated imagery</li>
<li>Digital installation art</li>
</ul>
<h2>Computer-generated visual media</h2>
<p>Digital visual art consists of either 2D visual information displayed on an electronic visual display or information mathematically translated into 3D information, viewed through perspective projection on an electronic visual display.</p>
<p><code>The simplest is 2D computer graphics which reflect how you might draw using a pencil and a piece of paper.</code></p>
<p>In this case, however, the image is on the computer screen and the instrument you draw with might be a tablet stylus or a mouse.</p>
<p>What is generated on your screen might appear to be drawn with a pencil, pen or paintbrush.</p>
<h2>Computer generated 3D still imagery</h2>
<p>3D graphics are created via the process of designing imagery from geometric shapes, polygons or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonuniform_rational_B-spline" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NURBS</a> curves to create three-dimensional objects and scenes for use in various media such as film, television, print, rapid prototyping, games/simulations and special visual effects.</p>
<p><em>The technology can enable collaboration, lending itself to sharing and augmenting by a creative effort similar to the open source movement, and the creative commons in which users can collaborate in a project to create unique pieces of art.</em></p>
<h2>Computer generated animated imagery</h2>
<p>Computer-generated animations are animations created with a computer, from digital models created by the 3D artists or procedurally generated.</p>
<p>The term is usually applied to works created entirely with a computer. Movies make heavy use of computer-generated graphics; they are called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer-generated_imagery" target="_blank" rel="noopener">computer-generated imagery</a> (CGI) in the film industry.</p>
<ul>
<li>In the 1990s, and early 2000s CGI advanced enough so that for the first time it was possible to create realistic 3D computer animation, although films had been using extensive computer images since the mid-70s.</li>
</ul>
<p>A number of modern films have been noted for their heavy use of photo realistic CGI.</p>
<h2>Digital installation art</h2>
<p>Digital installation art constitutes a broad field of activity and incorporates many forms. Some resemble video installations, particularly large scale works involving projections and live video capture.</p>
<p>By using projection techniques that enhance an audiences impression of sensory envelopment, many digital installations attempt to create immersive environments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/10/06/spectacular-and-colorful-designs-of-animals-in-polygonal-style/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to make full-color polygonal drawings</title>
		<link>/2018/07/21/how-to-make-full-color-polygonal-drawings/</link>
					<comments>/2018/07/21/how-to-make-full-color-polygonal-drawings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xczer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 06:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Polygon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/?p=361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The domestic dog is a member of the genus Canis (canines), which forms part of the wolf-like canids, and is the most widely abundant terrestrial...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The domestic dog is a member of the genus Canis (canines), which forms part of the wolf-like canids, and is the most widely abundant terrestrial carnivore.</p>
<p><strong>The dog</strong> and the extant gray wolf are sister taxa as modern wolves are not closely related to the wolves that were first domesticated, which implies that the direct ancestor of the dog is extinct.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog">The dog</a> was the first species to be domesticated and has been selectively bred over millennia for various behaviors, sensory capabilities, and physical attributes.</p>
<h3>Contents</h3>
<ol>
<li>Etymology</li>
<li>Terminology</li>
<li>Taxonomy</li>
<li>Origin</li>
<li>Biology</li>
</ol>
<h2>Etymology</h2>
<p>The term &#8220;domestic dog&#8221; is generally used for both domesticated and feral varieties. The English word dog comes from Middle English dogge, from Old English docga, a &#8220;powerful dog breed&#8221;.</p>
<blockquote><p>The term may derive from Proto-Germanic *dukkōn, represented in Old English finger-docce (&#8220;finger-muscle&#8221;) or (as suggested by Piotr Gąsiorowski) the Old English colour adjective dox, meaning &#8220;brown&#8221; or &#8220;tan&#8221;.</p></blockquote>
<p>In either case, the word seems to have been derived via the diminutive suffix -ga also seen in frogga &#8220;frog&#8221;, picga &#8220;pig&#8221;, stagga &#8220;stag&#8221;, wicga &#8220;beetle, worm&#8221;, among others.</p>
<h2>Terminology</h2>
<ul>
<li>The term dog typically is applied both to the species (or subspecies) as a whole, and any adult male member of the same.</li>
<li><del>An adult female is a bitch.</del></li>
<li>An adult male capable of reproduction is a stud.</li>
<li>An adult female capable of reproduction is a brood bitch, or brood mother.</li>
<li><em>Immature males or females (that is, animals that are incapable of reproduction) are pups or puppies.</em></li>
<li>A group of pups from the same gestation period is a litter.</li>
<li>The father of a litter is a sire. It is possible for one litter to have multiple sires.</li>
<li><strong>The mother of a litter is a dam.</strong></li>
<li>A group of any three or more adults is a pack.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Taxonomy</h2>
<p>In 1999, a study of mitochondrial DNA indicated that the domestic dog may <strong>have originated from multiple grey wolf populations</strong>, with the dingo and New Guinea singing dog &#8220;breeds&#8221; having developed at a time when human populations were more isolated from each other.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-376" src="http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/retriever-348572_1280-1024x685.jpg" alt="" width="718" height="480" /></p>
<p>In the third edition of Mammal Species of the World published in 2005, the mammalogist W. Christopher Wozencraft listed under the wolf Canis lupus its wild subspecies, and proposed two additional subspecies: &#8220;familiaris Linneaus, 1758 &#8221; and &#8220;dingo Meyer, 1793&#8221;.</p>
<p>Wozencraft included hallstromi &#8211; the New Guinea singing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog">dog</a> &#8211; as a taxonomic synonym for the dingo. Wozencraft referred to the mDNA study as a basis for his decisions.The inclusion of familiaris and dingo by Wozencraft under a &#8220;domestic dog&#8221; clade has been noted by other zoologists. <strong>This classification by Wozencraft is debated by zoologists</strong>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/07/21/how-to-make-full-color-polygonal-drawings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deer head polygon</title>
		<link>/2018/04/20/various-nature-polygons/</link>
					<comments>/2018/04/20/various-nature-polygons/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xczer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polygon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/various-nature-polygons/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This hand drawn polygon deer head is made up of 2 separate elements &#8211; a wireframe style outline and a solid shape. Use each element...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This hand drawn polygon deer head is made up of 2 separate elements &#8211; a wireframe style outline and a solid shape.</p>
<p>Use each element individually or combined. Create image masks for interesting effects (see the screenshots for examples).</p>
<p><strong>What&#8217;s included in the download package:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>An Adobe Illustrator document with each element on separate layers.</li>
<li>The polygon outlines supplied as an individual Illustrator 8.0 eps file</li>
<li>The solid shape supplied as an individual Illustrator 8.0 eps file.</li>
<li>A sample image mask template supplied as an Illustrator 8.0 eps file.</li>
<li>A Photoshop document with each element on a separate layer including an image mask.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Requirements for editing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The layered Illustrator file requires Adobe Illustrator CS or higher.</li>
<li>The Illustrator EPS files can be opened in most vector applications.</li>
<li>The layered Photoshop file requires Adobe Photoshop CS or higher.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/04/20/various-nature-polygons/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Vectorized Animals for Sketch</title>
		<link>/2018/04/18/10-vectorized-animals-for-sketch/</link>
					<comments>/2018/04/18/10-vectorized-animals-for-sketch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xczer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 03:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polygon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/10-vectorized-animals-for-sketch/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a pack has been hand drawn and then vectorized. Our goal was to achieve funny and cute animals while keeping the characteristic of...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a pack has been hand drawn and then vectorized. Our goal was to achieve funny and cute animals while keeping the characteristic of each of the animals.</p>
<p>All the illustrations can be downloaded freely at <a href="https://www.vectoropenstock.com/free-vectors/animals/">https://www.vectoropenstock.com/free-vectors/animals/</a> you can check the full gallery below.</p>
<div class="epcl-gallery"><ul class="columns-3 grid-container grid-parent np-tablet np-mobile">
                        <li class="grid-33 tablet-grid-33 mobile-grid-50">
                           <div class="wrapper">
                               <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/eagle.jpg" class="full-image mfp-image hover-effect" title="Eagle head"><span class="img cover" style="background: url(/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/eagle.jpg);"></span></a>
                           </div>
                        </li>
                        <li class="grid-33 tablet-grid-33 mobile-grid-50">
                           <div class="wrapper">
                               <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/dog-3275593_1920.jpg" class="full-image mfp-image hover-effect" title="Dog Face"><span class="img cover" style="background: url(/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/dog-3275593_1920.jpg);"></span></a>
                           </div>
                        </li>
                        <li class="grid-33 tablet-grid-33 mobile-grid-50">
                           <div class="wrapper">
                               <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cat.jpg" class="full-image mfp-image hover-effect" title="Poly Cat"><span class="img cover" style="background: url(/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cat.jpg);"></span></a>
                           </div>
                        </li>
                        <li class="grid-33 tablet-grid-33 mobile-grid-50">
                           <div class="wrapper">
                               <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/bird.jpg" class="full-image mfp-image hover-effect" title="Parrot Bird"><span class="img cover" style="background: url(/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/bird.jpg);"></span></a>
                           </div>
                        </li>
                        <li class="grid-33 tablet-grid-33 mobile-grid-50">
                           <div class="wrapper">
                               <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/deer-final.jpg" class="full-image mfp-image hover-effect" title=""><span class="img cover" style="background: url(/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/deer-final.jpg);"></span></a>
                           </div>
                        </li>
                        <li class="grid-33 tablet-grid-33 mobile-grid-50">
                           <div class="wrapper">
                               <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/small-poly-3350170_1920.jpg" class="full-image mfp-image hover-effect" title="Funny Rabbit"><span class="img cover" style="background: url(/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/small-poly-3350170_1920.jpg);"></span></a>
                           </div>
                        </li></ul><div class="clear"></div></div>
<p style="text-align: center;">Also you can download all vectorized animals directly from our website.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/04/18/10-vectorized-animals-for-sketch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
