<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Illustration &#8211; SingleClickBlog</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/illustration/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 23:35:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The best graphic designs of mountains for download</title>
		<link>/2018/10/06/the-best-graphic-illustrations-of-mountains-for-free-download/</link>
					<comments>/2018/10/06/the-best-graphic-illustrations-of-mountains-for-free-download/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xczer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 23:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Illustration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/?p=334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A mountain is a large landform that rises above the surrounding land in a limited area, usually in the form of a peak. A mountain...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A mountain is a <strong>large landform that rises above the surrounding land in a limited area</strong>, usually in the form of a peak. A mountain is generally steeper than a hill. Mountains are formed through tectonic forces or volcanism. These forces can locally raise the surface of the earth.</p>
<p>Mountains erode slowly through the action of rivers, weather conditions, and glaciers. A few mountains are isolated summits, but most occur in huge mountain ranges.</p>
<ol>
<li>Definition</li>
<li>Geology
<ol>
<li>Volcanoes</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mountain" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Block mountains</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Climate</li>
<li>Mountains and humans
<ol>
<li>Mountain societies and economies</li>
<li>Mountaneering</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<h2>Definition</h2>
<p>There is no universally accepted definition of a mountain. Elevation, volume, relief, steepness, spacing and continuity have been used as criteria for defining a mountain. In the Oxford English Dictionary a mountain is defined as:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;A natural elevation of the earth surface rising more or less abruptly from the surrounding level and attaining an altitude which, relatively to the adjacent elevation, is impressive or notable.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Whether a landform is called a mountain may depend on local usage. Mount Scott outside Lawton, Oklahoma is only 251 m (823 ft) from its base to its highest point. Whittow&#8217;s Dictionary of Physical Geography[2] states &#8220;Some authorities regard eminences above 600 metres (2,000 ft) as mountains, those below being referred to as hills.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Geology</h2>
<p>There are three main types of mountains: <strong>volcanic, fold, and block</strong>. All three types are formed from plate tectonics: when portions of the Earth&#8217;s crust move, crumple, and dive. Compressional forces, isostatic uplift and intrusion of igneous matter forces surface rock upward, creating a landform higher than the surrounding features.</p>
<p>The height of the feature makes it either a hill or, if higher and steeper, a mountain. <del>Major mountains tend to occur in long linear arcs</del>, indicating tectonic plate boundaries and activity.</p>
<h3>Volcanoes</h3>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-338" src="http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/provoke-art-3563931_1280-1024x723.jpg" alt="" width="718" height="507" /></p>
<p>Volcanoes are formed when a plate is pushed below another plate, or at a mid-ocean ridge or hotspot. At a depth of around 100 km, melting occurs in rock above the slab (due to the addition of water), and forms magma that reaches the surface. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mountain" target="_blank" rel="noopener">When the magma reaches the surface</a>, it often builds a volcanic mountain, such as a shield volcano or a stratovolcano.</p>
<p>Examples of volcanoes include <em>Mount Fuji in Japan and Mount Pinatubo in the Philippines</em>. The magma does not have to reach the surface in order to create a mountain: magma that solidifies below ground can still form dome mountains, such as Navajo Mountain in the US.</p>
<h3>Fold mountains</h3>
<p>Fold mountains occur when two plates collide: shortening occurs along thrust faults and the crust is overthickened.</p>

<p>Since the less dense continental crust &#8220;floats&#8221; on the denser mantle rocks beneath, the weight of any crustal material forced upward to form hills, plateaus or mountains must be balanced by the buoyancy force of a much greater volume forced downward into the mantle.</p>
<p><code>Thus the continental crust is normally much thicker under mountains, compared to lower lying areas.</code></p>
<p>Rock can fold either symmetrically or asymmetrically. The upfolds are anticlines and the downfolds are synclines: in asymmetric folding there may also be recumbent and overturned folds. The Jura Mountains are an example of fold mountains.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/10/06/the-best-graphic-illustrations-of-mountains-for-free-download/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watercolor effect in vector landscape design</title>
		<link>/2018/06/23/watercolor-effect-in-vector-landscape-design/</link>
					<comments>/2018/06/23/watercolor-effect-in-vector-landscape-design/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xczer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 06:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Illustration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/?p=356</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A landscape is the visible features of an area of land, its landforms and how they integrate with natural or man-made features. A landscape includes...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A landscape is the visible features of an area of land, its landforms and how they integrate with natural or man-made features.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Landscape" target="_blank" rel="noopener">landscape</a> includes the physical elements of geophysically defined landforms such as (ice-capped) mountains, hills, water bodies such as rivers, lakes, ponds and the sea, living elements of land cover including <del>indigenous vegetation</del>, human elements including different forms of land use, <strong>buildings and structures</strong>, and transitory elements such as lighting and weather conditions.</p>
<blockquote><p>Combining both their physical origins and the cultural overlay of human presence, often created over millennia, landscapes reflect a living synthesis of people and place that is vital to local and national identity.</p></blockquote>
<p>The character of a landscape helps define the self-image of the people who inhabit it and a sense of place that differentiates one region from other regions.</p>
<p><code>It is the dynamic backdrop to people’s lives. Landscape can be as varied as farmland, a landscape park, or wilderness.</code></p>
<p><strong>The Earth</strong> has a vast range of landscapes, including the icy landscapes of polar regions, mountainous landscapes, vast arid desert landscapes, islands and coastal landscapes, densely forested or wooded landscapes including past <strong>boreal forests and tropical rainforests</strong>, and agricultural landscapes of temperate and tropical regions.</p>
<p>The activity of modifying the visible features of an area of land is referred to as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Landscape" target="_blank" rel="noopener">landscaping</a>.</p>
<h2>Definition and etymology</h2>
<p>There are several <strong>definitions of what constitutes a landscape</strong>, depending on context. In common usage however, a landscape refers either to all the visible features of an area of land (usually rural), often considered in terms of aesthetic appeal, or to a pictorial representation of an area of countryside, specifically within the genre of landscape painting.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-372" src="http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/landscape-404072_1280-1024x682.jpg" alt="" width="718" height="478" /></p>
<p>When people deliberately improve the <em>aesthetic appearance</em> of a piece of land—by changing contours and vegetation, etc.—it is said to have been landscaped, though the result may not constitute a landscape according to some definitions.</p>
<p>There are several words that are frequently associated with the word landscape:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Scenery</strong>: The natural features of a landscape considered in terms of their appearance, esp. when picturesque: spectacular views of mountain scenery.</li>
<li><strong>Setting</strong>: In works of narrative (especially fictional), it includes the historical moment in time and geographic location in which a story takes place, and helps initiate the main backdrop and mood for a story.</li>
<li><strong>Picturesque</strong>: The word literally means &#8220;in the manner of a picture; fit to be made into a picture&#8221;, and used as early as 1703 (Oxford English Dictionary), and derived from an Italian term pittoresco, &#8220;in the manner of a painter&#8221;.</li>
<li><strong>A view</strong>: &#8220;A sight or prospect of some landscape or extended scene; an extent or area covered by the eye from one point&#8221; (OED).</li>
<li><strong>Wilderness</strong>: An uncultivated, uninhabited, and inhospitable region.</li>
<li><strong>Cityscape</strong> (also townscape): The urban equivalent of a landscape. In the visual arts a cityscape (urban landscape) is an artistic representation, such as a painting, drawing, print or photograph, of the physical aspects of a city or urban area.</li>
<li><strong>Seascape</strong>: A photograph, painting, or other work of art which depicts the sea, in other words an example of marine art.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Physical landscape</h2>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Landscape" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Geomorphology</a> is the scientific study of the origin and evolution of topographic and bathymetric features created by physical or chemical processes operating at or near Earth&#8217;s surface.</p>
<p><strong> Geomorphologists</strong> seek to understand why landscapes look the way they do, to understand landform history and dynamics and to predict changes through a combination of field observations, physical experiments and numerical modeling.</p>
<p><del>Geomorphology</del> is practiced within physical geography, geology, geodesy, engineering geology, archaeology and geotechnical engineering. This broad base of interests contributes to many research styles and interests within the field.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/06/23/watercolor-effect-in-vector-landscape-design/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Awesome Vectorized Car</title>
		<link>/2017/09/24/15-awesome-vectorized-car/</link>
					<comments>/2017/09/24/15-awesome-vectorized-car/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xczer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 01:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Illustration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://estudiopatagon.com/themes/wordpress/recov3/15-awesome-vectorized-car/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looking at other designers’ work can bring a new wave of creativity and inspiration. For today’s inspiration, we have put together a draw-dropping collection of...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking at other designers’ work can bring a new wave of creativity and inspiration. For today’s inspiration, we have put together a draw-dropping collection of creative car vectors for you.</p>
<p>These vector designs are so realistic and amazing that you will fall in love with them instantly. Creating a good vector car design requires loads of time and efforts, but as you’ll can see from these masterpieces, it’s certainly worth all the time and effort in the end. Now check out the car collection!</p>
<h2 id="chevroletcamarobyhaegelejoan">Chevrolet Camaro by Haegele Joan</h2>
<p>This Chevrolet Camaro car looks real when you first glance at it. The artist has paid attention even to the minute details. The artist has also uploaded different images to show the progress of work which is a nice touch.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1471880294403-9e755e0f89d6?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;q=80&amp;fm=jpg&amp;crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;w=1080&amp;fit=max&amp;s=dda79af05ba8b07edf4ead6000fe4971" alt="" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2017/09/24/15-awesome-vectorized-car/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
